Dr Sharda Rai

GC 02, Indorama India Pvt Ltd, Jagdishpur Industrial Area, Jagdishpur, Amethi, UP

9999424609,9953109953,shardaraimusic@gmail.com

MUSIC TEACHER

Career Summary

Certified music teacher offering over ten years experience working with students in both western and classical music, distinguished by professionalism and perfect communication skills, demonstrated in pleasant personality and effective listening abilities.

Proficiency Offered

- Advanced knowledge in teaching students using various music instruments.
- Proficient with music instruments: veena, harmoniums & tabla
- Thorough familiarity with classical music.
- Comprehensive background in leading all aspects of musical shows.

Objective – To obtain Music Teaching position utilizing comprehensive teaching experience/knowledge, guiding students to love and become proficient with art of music.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

EMPLOYMENT BACKGROUND

- Worked as a Music Teacher in Sangeet Bharti Institute Delhi from 2005 to 2009
- Worked as a Music Teacher at N K Bargodia School Dwarka since 2008 to 2009
- Worked as a Music Teacher in Queens Valley School Dwarka since July 2012 to March 2014
- Worker a music teacher in Vanasthli Public School Noida from July 2014 to June 2015.

NOTABLE CAREER HIGHLIGHTS

- Have given music lessons on the following instruments: Veena, Harmonium
- Educational Programs Developed lesson plans and schedules.
- Performed in Prayag Sangeet Samiti Samaroh

- Awarded 2nd prize in Lata Mangeskar Award in yr 2000.
- Participated in many youth festivals in Delhi University from 1997 to 2003.

Music Teaching:

- Guided individuals and groups in playing music instruments and applications.
- Guided and offered music lessons and tutorials for diverse college students.
- Teach prescribed music syllabus, including musical concepts and performance, composition and sight reading and listening skills, in context of style and genre.

Music Programmes:

- Guided students participating in inter-school musical shows, competitions and different musical events.
- Coordinated with school authorities in organizing school festivals and shows.

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS

- Ph.D from University of Delhi
- M. Phil with first div from University of Delhi
- M.A in Music with First Div APS University, Rewa (M.P)
- Prabhakar-Music Diploma of 6 Yr from Prayag Sangeet Samiti Allahabad (U.P)